Finding Aid for Delmar D. Gibbons Papers, 1932-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Delmar D. Gibbons papers 1932-1967
Gibbons, Delmar D., 1913-
851366 Aa 2
State and national Prohibition Party officer and candidate, executive chairman of the Prohibition National Committee, editor of the National Statesman, 1963-1967; correspondence, campaign material, news releases, scrapbooks, photographs, and printed material.
2 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Delmar Gibbons (donor no. 4130 ) and came to the library in 1967.
The collection is open to research.
Delmar D. Gibbons, born in 1913, was long active in the state and national Prohibition Party campaigns and issues, both as an officer in the organization and as a candidate for office in Michigan. He served as member of the state central committee beginning in 1947. He also served as executive chairman of the Prohibition National Committee, and editor of the party newspaper National Statesman from 1963 to 1967. As a candidate, Gibbons ran for the US House of Representatives from Kalamazoo in 1946, for the Michigan House of Representatives in 1950 and 1952, for the University of Michigan Board of Regents in 1959, and for governor in 1960.
The Delmar Gibbons papers document his activities in support of prohibition and in Michigan state politics. The collection includes correspondence, campaign material, news releases, scrapbooks, photographs, and printed material. The collection is arranged into the following series: Prohibition Party election and campaign materials; Other Prohibition and Temperance Organizations; Scrapbooks; and Other materials
Subjects:
Gibbons, Delmar D., 1913-; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Presidents--United States--Election--1964.; Prohibition--United States.; Prohibition Party (Mich.); Prohibition National Committee (U.S.); Temperance--United States.; United States--Politics and government--1929-1933.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Demonstrations.; Gibbons, Delmar D., 1913-; Kalamazoo (Mich.); Political parades and rallies.; Prohibition--United States.; Prohibition Party (Mich.); Prohibition National Committee (U.S.); Stills.; Temperance.
Contributors:
Blake, Edward Everett, 1875-1947.; Casey, William R.; Childres, Jack.; Conover, Milton, 1890-; Davis, Oscar N.; Decker, Rutherford L.; Dilley, Robert D.; Dodge, Earl Farwell, 1932-; Hammaker, Wilbur Emery, 1876-1968.; Holtwick, Enoch A., 1880?-1972.; Ivy, A. C. (Andrew Conway), 1893-1978; Kohler, Julia B., d. 1969.; Ludwig, Oscar C.; Martin, Clarence S.; Molesworth, Jack E.; Munn, Earle Harold, 1903-; Shaw, Mark Revell, 1889-; Tooze, Ruth Tibbits, 1901-; Van Poperin, Joan.; Walker, Chester, Mrs.; Watkins, Victor.; Watson, Claude A., 1885-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Prohibition Party election and campaign materials
  The Prohibition Party election and campaign materials series is arranged chronologically. A selective index to correspondents provides citations to letters form some of the more significant correspondents.
  - 1933-June 1966, 28 folders (Box 1)
  - July 1966-June 1967 undated, 5 folders (Box 2)
- Other Prohibition and Temperance Organizations
  - Temperance Education Council and the American 1957-1969 (Box 2)
  - Christian Committee of the Michigan Prohibition Party (Box 2)
    (include the treasurer's reports)
  - Michigan Prohibition Party papers 1957-1964 (Box 2)
    (include expense account of the state chairman and list of contributors with amounts)
  - Michigan Prohibition Party radio broadcasts 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Beldon C. Hoyt autobiography and copies of poetry (Box 2)
  - Kalamazoo County Prohibition Committee minutes 1953-1958 (Box 2)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1932-1942 (Box 2)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - 1946-1948 (Box 2)
  - 1948-1954 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook of Mrs. F.C. Easterly 1934 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook of Mrs. F.C. Easterly 1935 (Box 2)
- Other materials
  - Prohibition Party worker's handbook 1947-1948 (Box 2)
  - Prohibition Party worker's handbook 1963 (Box 2)
  - Prohibition Party worker's handbook 1963 (Box 2)
  - Prohibition Party worker's handbook 1963 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Prohibition Party photographs (Box 2)
  - Prohibition Party Printed material (Box 2)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Blake, Edward Everett, 1875-1947.
August 20, 1936, October 2, 1940
Casey, William R.
March 6, 1967
Childres, Jack
September 17, 1965
Conover, Milton, 1890-
Nov. 11, 1962, Dec. 13, 1962, May 18, 1963, May 28, 1963, June 11, 1963, June 14, Sept. 16, 1963, Nov. 26, 1963, Aug. 17, 1964, Sept. 26, 1964, Oct. 8, 1964, Dec. 27, 1965, Jan. 18, 1966, Oct. 17, 1966, Jan. 21, 1967, Apr. 11, 1967, Apr. 14, 1967, Apr. 24, 1967
Davis, Oscar N.
Feb. 28, 1965, Mar. 6, 1965, Apr. 8, 1965, May 29, 1965, June 2, 1965
Decker, Rutherford L.
June 9, 1960, June 21, 1963, July 23, 1963, Sept. 10, 1963, Oct. 29, 1963, Mar. 17, 1964, July 23, 1964, July 27, 1964, Apr. 5, 1966, Dec. 7, 1966
Dilley, Robert D.
Dec. 16, 1964, Dec. 25, 1964, Jan. 11, 1965, Jan. 25, 1965, Apr. 8, 1965, Apr. 9, 1965, May 29, 1965
Dodge, Earl Farwell, 1932-
Apr. 6, 1963, Aug. 12, 1963, Mar. 21, 1964, Feb. 16, 1966, Apr. 26, 1966, many letters in Apr., May, June, 1967
Hammaker, Wilbur Emery, 1876-1968.
May 31, 1958, Jan. 15, 1964, May 26, 1964, June 4, 1964, Aug. 15, 1964, Oct. 6, 1964, Mar. 21, 1965, Oct. 27, 1965, Dec. 8, 1965, Apr. 21, 1966, Nov. 10, 1966, Dec. 19, 1966, Apr. 14, 1967
Holtwick, Enoch A, 1880?-1972.
June 18, 1963
Ivy, A. C. (Andrew Conway), 1893-
June 18, 1963, June 29, 1964
Kohler, Julia B., d. 1969.
Sept. 24, 1966
Ludwig, Oscar C.
Mar. 2, 1965, Mar. 4, 1965, Oct. 23, 1965
Martin, Clarence S.
Oct. 9, 1964
Molesworth, Jack E.
Jan. 15, 1965
Munn, Earle Harold, 1904-
July 27, 1946, Aug. 8, 1946, Aug. 13, 1946, Aug. 19, 1946, Aug. 26, 1946, Sept. 15, 1946, Sept. 6, 1946, Dec. 13, 1948, Feb. 21, 1949, Oct. 15, 1949, Oct.26, 1950, May 19, 1963, Aug. 10, 1963, Nov. 4, 1963, Nov. 19, 1963, July 1964 (telegram to Barry Goldwater)
Shaw, Mark Revell, 1889
Judy 10, 1963, Sept. 10, 1963, Sept. 17, 1963, Sept. 25, 1963, Oct. 5, 1963, Oct. 21, 1963, Jan. 9, 1964, Jan. 21, 1964, Apr. 27, 1964, June 9, 1964, July 13, 1964, July 22, 1964, Aug. 19, 1964, Oct. 1, 1964, Oct. 29, 1964, Dec. 9, 1964, Dec. 31, 1964, May 23, 1965, June 4, 1965, Aug. 17, 1965
Tooze, Ruth Tibbits, 1901-
May 21 1963, June 11, 1963, Sept. 30, 1963, Nov. 16, 1963, July 24, 1964, Aug. 24, 1964, May 14, 1965, July 27, 1965, Aug. 13, 1965, Aug. 26, 1965, Feb. 21, 1966, Apr. 7, 1966, May 1, 1966, Aug. 8, 1966, Oct. 21, 1966, Nov. 10, 1966, Nov. 14, 1966, Apr. 21, 1967
Van Poperin, Joan
Feb. 28, 1965
Walker, Chester, Mrs.
May 11, 1967
Watkins, Victor
May 1966 (Gibbons replied on May 26, 1966)
Watson, Claude A., 1885-
June 20, 1963, June 27, 1963, Aug. 12, 1963, Aug. 19, 1963, Sept. 26, 1963, Feb. 7. 1964, Feb. 15, 1966, Feb. 17, 1966, Dec. 7, 1966, May 11, 1967